<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-18T20:24:16+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Petri Dish</title><subtitle>An amazing website.</subtitle><author><name>Miguel Miranda</name><email>general@l3m.dev</email></author><entry><title type="html">A Study in Scarlet. Also an experiment in writing and Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/start/github/jekyll/a-study-in-scarlet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Study in Scarlet. Also an experiment in writing and Jekyll" /><published>2020-07-18T16:16:15+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-18T16:16:15+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/start/github/jekyll/a-study-in-scarlet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/start/github/jekyll/a-study-in-scarlet/">&lt;p&gt;Maintaining a blog is something that never attracted me or piqued my interest in the slightest. Quite possibly still doesn’t. Technology and experimenting always did though, since I disassembled my first electronic appliance. That experiment brought down the fuse in my house and nearly gave my mother a heart attack, but lets dig through that another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, like most engineers/architects and others that love to research and experiment on the tech space, I of course always kept detailed notes in a repository that I can return to and reference in the future to others. He he he…  Of course not. I try my best, but from paper Moleskine notepads to actual files in Notepad++, nothing really felt both easy to write and search/maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my experience with Github Enterprise use since I’ve introduced it in new projects at work (couple of years back), it is clear it can do more more than being a great source version control system. The version control and collaborative features that make upt its strength in development are quite useful to manage documentation. Usually documentation is a lesser child, and that is prevalent on startups and larger companies alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On enterprise settings where everything must be in a word or pdf document in sharepoint, with revision tags and colors up the wazoo, documenting becomes something one dreads. Since I end up doing a lot of R&amp;amp;D and exploration in my current company, I need to document a lot to handover/document/maintain knowledge as it moves to regular development and ops teams. I needed to change this dead of writing documentation. No silver bullet seems to exist, but I found a way that suits me and my teams better, using github and markdown for everything. Wow, revolutionary right? Not really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With different utilities like Pandoc I can generate documents based on my companies template with Markdown. Exactly the same documentation i keep on github with our developers and maintain by our architects and developers, which generates a nice pretty document (both Word and PFD)with all the bells and whistles which can be uploaded to Sharepoint like our managers and auditors are used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you ask wisely, “what does that have to do with starting a blog”?! This is not a blog. This is where I will document my experiments as I would like to share them and keep them, being them in tech or perhaps just a trip. This is a Markdown file I write in VS Code and put on Github. This is me experimenting with Jekyll that generates a full site based on these post files. This is a bunch of experiments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/A_Study_in_Scarlet&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Miguel Miranda</name></author><summary type="html">Maintaining a blog is something that never attracted me or piqued my interest in the slightest. Quite possibly still doesn’t. Technology and experimenting always did though, since I disassembled my first electronic appliance. That experiment brought down the fuse in my house and nearly gave my mother a heart attack, but lets dig through that another time.</summary></entry></feed>